We would do whatever we have to to make students feel safe.
In the past week, we've seen thousands of students here at the state capitol asking us to do one thing,
and that is to ban assault weapons.
Nowhere in this bill do I hear the word, or do I see the word, guns, AR-15s, assault weapons,
the things that actually are traumatizing and terrorizing these young people.
And so my question to the sponsor is that this bill seems to be a Band-Aid.
It seems to be a white flag of surrender when what we need to make our young people safe
is a deep surgery of our system that places firearms above the lives of our children.
If I may, Mr. Speaker, I want to read from Jeremiah 614 that says,
Representative Jones, that's outside the caption.
You need to stay on the caption of the bill.
I'm sorry, but you have to stay within the discussion on the bill that is outside.
So if you would like to address questions or talk about school safety, that is welcome.
Representative Jones.
Thank you, Mr. Speaker.
They offer superficial treatments for my people's mortal wound.
They give assurances of peace when there is no peace.
Representative Jones, once again, that is not on the topic of the bill.
Even your colleagues are nodding yes.
I'm asking you again, please stay on the topic of the bill.
If you have questions or statements based on that topic of the bill, then please continue.
You're recognized, Representative Jones.
Thank you, Mr. Speaker.
Mr. Speaker, the point I'm trying to make is that this bill is not about school safety.
It will not make our students safer.
Representative Lambert told the media that we must fortify our schools,
even if it means putting tanks outside our schools.
That is disturbing.
I don't think any of us want to live in a world like that.
Well, we make our schools militarized zones simply because we refuse to address the real issue,
which is easy access to military-grade weapons,
which is easy access to weapons of war on our streets.
And so, again, I'm deeply troubled that we are making this political statement today
by trying to act like we're doing something that is not going to do anything to prevent what occurred.
More police officers in schools.
Yesterday they passed the bill to armed teachers.
This is not going to make our students safe.
And I think that we owe it to these young people, the thousands here,
who we tried to speak for when we were silenced,
the thousands who are gathered outside demanding that we take real action
to address the crisis of easy access to military-grade weapons in this state.
And so, with that, I must say that I cannot support this bill
because this bill is a Band-Aid.
It is a white flag of surrender.
And it is not action that will make our students safe.
And no student, I talked to thousands of students,
and not one of them said, this is what we want.
And I think that we as elected officials have a moral responsibility
to listen to these young people who are on the front lines,
who are terrified, who are here crying and pleading for their lives.
And so, my question is to the sponsor,
would you be willing to add some provision
or to have a conversation about banning assault weapons
to move our state forward?
That's what these young people are asking.
Would you be willing to do that, Chairman White?
Representative Jones, Chairman White.
Thank you, Mr. Speaker.
Representative Jones, look at me.
Look at the other 97.
This is exactly what we're trying to do.
I have been up here 14 years.
You have been in this assembly for two months, three months.
We as a legislative body are constantly looking for ideas.
But when things break down where we cannot continue
to create and discuss ideas, this is where we get to,
and this is what has led to this day.
I used to be a school principal.
I would literally step in front of anything
for the protection of those little ones in my school.
You assume that because we do not have everything that you may want
or anyone else may want this bill,
that this is a bad bill.
We are trying to put things together to a starting place.
So I answer your question with this.
Yes, we've been trying to communicate with you
and others on this floor since January.
And here we are today.
We have a good bill.
And if you would work with us,
we could have even a better bill in the future.
That is my response to you.
Out of order.
I got you, Leader Camper.
Thank you.
Representative Jones, you're recognized.
Thank you, Mr. Speaker.
To my colleague, Chairman White.
Sorry, the five minutes are up.
Representative Hardaway.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Mr. Speaker.
Thank you to the gentleman in the well.
And thank you for making an attempt at providing a safe environment for our children and our staff
and the visitors to the schools.
And I agree that this is only one step.
But my concern is it addresses symptoms, that it doesn't address the problems.
And as Chairman White said, we've got to do better bills in the future,
especially in the case of mental health for our students, for staff, for teachers,
because everything that we're dealing with now has traumatized all of the above.
And that's not even mentioning.
Thank you.